Johar to all the students and
devotees, I am Sachin Chandra. Like every
year, this year too we have reached
Preet Bihar Colony located on JC Malik Road.
And this is Khokan Babu's pond,
as you can see, our former
ward councilor Priyaranjan ji
is also present here and all the devotees
and worshippers are present here. You
can see the Kalash installation process is going on
because today is Saptami, the first day of Saptami, the
first day of Mata,
from today itself, worship and prayers are
established in the temples and today's
process is going on.
[Music]
[Praise]
A
[Music]
You can see the devotees installing the Kalash,
everyone is going. This pavilion has been built by ward councilor
Priyaranjan ji
and
all the people are participating here. You can see
this puja program is held with great pomp and show through the inauguration of the Bangoli. Like every year,
this year too it is being celebrated.
You can see how
this time with simplicity we have to follow all the
rules and regulations of the lockdown.  We have to follow the rules, that is why let's go and
visit the mother, all of
you be ready,
we will visit the mother, say
Durga Mata ki
Jai,
then we will know
what message he wants to give to the public through our former ward councilor Priya Ranjan, let's
know,
today is the day of Mata's Kola, it is the day of Saptami
and today we have
brought the mother from the nearby pond to our pavilion
and we will
worship her from the Dwi to Dashara in a very good manner and following the Covid protocol
and will worship her in a very good manner
and our
prayer to the mother will be that she should free us from this corona, give us
complete freedom and there should be
peace and happiness in the whole world,
with this belief we are worshipping the mother
and we will definitely be free from Covid, Jai
Ma Durga, Jai Ma Durga,
we were just taking a byte from ward councilor
Priyaranjan, Shri Priyaranjan ji,
you heard his blessings, you must have liked it
very much, you will
get inspiration from these and
I wish everyone a bright future,
thank you, let's go  Let's take a
byte from the next committee member, we also know what they have to say,
tell me your name first, Ma'am Rekha Mitra,
so let me tell you this, I want to tell her that
we wish that the four days of puja go well here,
everyone likes it, everyone is fine
and what message do you want to give, let's
maintain a little distance from this corona, let's all have a good puja,
this is my best wishes to all of us,
Bala Kajal Dat, we had a lot of fun for four days,
so let's meet the next committee member,
what does he have to say,
what is his reaction, under this Durga
Puja festival of 2021, let's what is your name,
Ma'am, my name is Papiya, so
how much do you enjoy celebrating this puja, we
enjoy it a lot, very very much, this is
our 11th year and
we enjoy this puja a lot, I
mean, what should I say, it started from a very small place,
but today we feel
that in the entire Hirapur, our temple, our
mother, is the best, the best,
Preet Bihar Colony  It is Durga Puja and the
credit for this goes to Ranjan Bhaiya, Priya
Ranjan Bhaiya, we all are also there but
Priya Ranjan Bhaiya does a lot for us, it is
very good and we enjoy it a lot,
there is distribution of bhog and puja, let us
also ask that this
time a
lot of rules are being followed as per the corona protocol
due to which it has been said that there should be a 5 feet
idol, you
cannot put rice lights etc. on your puja pandal, you
cannot decorate it in a very decorative way, so what is their problem with this and
what problems are they facing due to this,
we will also understand that and if
instead of a 5 feet idol, an 8 feet
idol comes, will corona
spread, so we will know all this
from the audience, so what is your name
Savita Chandra, so from Savita Chandra we will
know that under this corona
protocol which has been prescribed by the state government,
Jharkhand government,
what is their reaction in this, we will know, it is very good to follow the
rules, it is very
good  That's it, thank you so madam, my
question was that as it was
said that this time the 5 feet idol is within the corona protocol, so
if instead of 5 feet, there is an 8 feet idol, will
we get corona? Will we have to be
absolutely safe and be very careful, will have to
wear masks etc. So,
thank you, let us know from Shamal Rai that
how much he enjoys this Durga Puja festival, how
happy he feels, how much joy he feels
and by doing this, what
message he wants to give to him under this puja,
we will also know his reaction,
let us go,
best wishes,
Ja
Ut
Manu Durga
Puja,
today
re faith ma Durga daja
ne mane ma courage shakti
sanch ma
Durga Manoj
da Sukumar Sarkar Sukumar Sarkar mudra eva samani
women
eva
today today ma power eva pad Virat
sahg sa
today my
rb go
ahead many thousands of
manu sacred samana
slogan
man re manre namo namo Gauri namo Narayan dakh da se kar ta jani
tum sangh tum jani purush ma kamani
Ram rup dha man mane ma
man  Ra chane sene mom ma a bo ja ja Suma naam ra mana ba chan bane Jai bole charan charan kha ja khan na tu na bapanni k di ma ra charan p karo Maa Kali Kale ka tug tu gu Durga Durga
bole cha
Durga so let us
know from Manoj Majumdar how much joy he gets by celebrating this holy puja
and what is his reaction
and what message he wants to give to the society, so
we will know all this, okay
let us know, Namaskar, today is Maha Saptami, Maha Saptami is the auspicious day, everyone
present there will be Sharad Preeti,
good wishes, greetings, JC Mallick Road Durga Puja
Committee, Durga Puja is being organised for four days, in
Sundar Park, Fuller Garden and temple,
welcome to see the year, today
Durga Puja is being organised by many people, we are invoking Anara with great joy,
Durga Puja can be celebrated with joy and celebration, we can get
up with it, we know that there is a physical and
mental terror, we are very weak but
All this power blessings are with us, we have overcome everything, we
worship mother, we worship friend and mother's blessings, we are clean, we are
happy, we worship with all our might,
thank you, so let us first know from
Lopa Mudra, okay, Madam
Lopa Mudra, this festival and this
festival of Durga is the destroyer of Durga,
that is why she is called Durga, so
what is her opinion on this and she means how much
power she gets by worshipping Mother Durga, how much
power she feels, she prays,
we will know all these things,
let us, Advocate Lopa Mudra Chakraborty,
like Mullick
Dhanbad,
care for the public 365 days and she is
a woman, she plays the role of mother
aunt and she plays the role of
Durga, worship her 365 days and
enjoy it a lot and today in the new
paper we have always respected the national language
Hindi, we respect the national language Hindi,
people speak Hindi only, I,
Advocate Lopa Mudra, like Dhanbad, live in a village
and we  We celebrate Durga Puja
in a grand manner
because we women are considered to be the motherly form.
That is why we women want to adopt whatever
system of Maa Durga is there in many
ways
and we enjoy it a lot
because we are working ladies 365 days a year
and have to think about others and
think for everyone. People have their own profession and are
busy in that. But this
atmosphere of Durga Puja
makes us wait so much and
we enjoy it a lot. Today is Maha
Saptami. On the morning of Maha Saptami, we have come
for the entry of Nav Patrika Patrika
and we have brought it
here.
We will invoke Maa Durga again from tomorrow.
Thank you. So let's go and have darshan of the Mother.
Look, this is the decoration of the Mother.
You can see in the background that it has been
painted red and this is making the
idol of the Mother very beautiful and attractive.
You can see the Maha Pandit, who is a great
Pandit, is preparing for the puja.
I would like to show the decoration above in front of me,
so you all are watching the live telecast of
Jharkhand Math
Zone
[Prasha]
Ja B Mar Ma Ru Ma
Patha
Bo
Thora Ha,
see, at this position, all of you can get to know
when which puja is,
okay, by coming directly to the pandal, you can
find out
which puja is going to be held on which date, you can
get this very easily, you do
n't have to ask the pandit or anyone, you all
come here on the right side corner,
in Preet Bihar Kauli, the Durga
mandap where Durga puja is going on,
you can see this thing, so
now we will move from here
and proceed towards the next puja pandal